dhsprogram.com 2019-12-16

# The DHS Program - Privacy Policy

## Privacy Policy

Effective Date: June 25, 2018

Privacy Policy Notice | Collected Personal Information | Use of Personal Information | Cookies | Contact

**Privacy Policy Notice**

* * *

Individuals share personal information with The DHS Program in two major ways: 1) passively, through visits to our websites and downloading our mobile app, and 2) actively, through submitting personal information to download DHS datasets, post questions on the User Forum, comment on the blog, apply to and participate in online and in-person workshops, subscribe for email alerts, and through direct email correspondence with DHS Program staff.

This Privacy Policy applies to the web pages, mobile applications, workshops, online services, electronic mail, and related content operated, or controlled by The DHS Program and its partners or alliances, subcontractors, or third-party vendors. Websites controlled by The DHS Program include [The DHS Program website](https://www.dhsprogram.com/), STATcompiler, Spatial Data Repository, The DHS Program User Forum, The DHS Program Online Learning Platform, The DHS Program API, and The DHS Program Blog.

This Privacy Policy may be supplemented or amended from time to time at our discretion. 

**Personal Information Collected by The DHS Program**

* * *

**Information collected automatically**  
We may collect information through the use of various technologies to enhance your experience on our sites. For example, we may store the IP address from which you access our sites, and other information used for website analytics and project monitoring and evaluation. We do not collect or track any personal information through these automated processes. See Cookies for more information.

**Information you voluntarily provide to us**  
You may choose to give us personal information directly in a variety of situations. For example, you may give us your personal information by contacting us directly or sending us personal information through any of our sites or social media platforms. 

We store and use your personal data for internal purposes only, such as for confirming and tracking your publication order, subscription or registration, and generating program statistics to monitor trends in usage and activities for management and reporting purposes.

**Use of Personal Information**

* * *

Most of our systems collect user IP information for tracking purposes as well as email addresses for communications with users. This information is only used for legitimate purposes, such as monitoring the use of our products and reporting trends and never shared outside The DHS Program or USAID.

Please be aware that when you voluntarily make your personal information available for viewing by third parties online, such as on social media or a public message board, your information can be viewed, collected, and used by individuals and organizations outside of The DHS Program.

**Datasets Download Accounts**  
The DHS Program collects personal information when a user applies for a dataset download account. This information is necessary to ensure a legitimate person is requesting the data, and for communicating with you. Learn more about why we require registration.

**Publications Ordering**  
The DHS Program collects personal information when a user requests a publication to be shipped by mail. This information is necessary to fulfill the request. 

**User Forum**  
The DHS Program collects personal information when a user registers for an account on the DHS User Forum (userforum.dhprogram.com). This information is necessary to complete the registration process. 

**Workshop Applications**  
The DHS Program collects personal information when a user applies to participate in a DHS workshop or training. This is necessary to ensure the participant is qualified, and to arrange for workshop participation, including travel and lodging if applicable. Once the applicants are selected, they are contacted to confirm their acceptance. We may also retain workshop participants’ personal information to keep a record of previous workshops they have attended. 

**eLearning Courses  **  
The DHS Program collects and stores personal information when a user is registered to participate in an online eLearning course at learning.dhsprogram.com. This information is necessary to allow the user to access the system.

**Cookies**

* * *

Cookies are essentially tokens of information, such as preferences and passwords, which some Web servers collect from you when you access them. That data are stored on your hard drive – not on the website's server. Whenever you visit a site that uses "cookies", the server looks for its cookie on your hard drive and, if found, reads the information it stored there. 

The DHS Program websites use cookies only to authenticate your identity, and to serve technical purposes, like providing smooth navigation while you are visiting our website. Traffic statistics are collected anonymously and aggregated, and no information is traceable to any specific individual. The DHS Program does not collect personal information through the use of cookies.

Cookies may also be set by third-party providers, such as Google Analytics and YouTube, on The DHS Program websites. The DHS Program will not share any information associated with cookies with individuals not connected with the administration of our website, or with anyone outside The DHS Program.

**Contact Us**

* * *

If you have questions regarding this Privacy Policy, your personal data, or you want to let us know about our Sites please contact us at [privacy@dhsprogram.com](mailto:privacy@dhsprogram.com). 

The DHS Program  
ICF  
530 Gaither Road, Suite 500  
Rockville, MD 20850 USA

Tel: +1 (301) 407-6500  
Fax: +1 (301) 407-6501

Back to Top
